A Guide to the Ancel E. Nunn Papers, 1943-2008
Nunn, Ancel E., Papers
- Stored remotely at Library Storage Facility (LSF):
  - Ancel Nunn papers 1943-2008
    - Patron Files 1968-2008 (Box 2008-252/8)
      - Muse, Martha T. 1976-1989 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Nichols, Dr. Charles 1976-1993 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Nichols, Robert 1972-1982 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Nunn, Charles 1972-1995 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - O’Brien, John 1999 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Ogden, Julia (Sally) – DISTY’S 1991 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - O’Grady, Jack Galleries 1974-1998 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Oman, Fred 1969-1987 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Osgood, Bill 1973-1976 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Pace, Dr. James R. 1972-1991 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Parsons, James 1975-1999 (Box 2008-252/10)
      - Pendaland, Jerry 1980 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Perley, Mrs. Richard 1975-1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Perlitz, Jerry 1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Peterson, Richard 1994 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Pinkston, C.J. Mr. Mrs. 1983-2006 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Price, Dr. Downey 1975-2007 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Price, Fred 1972 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Ramsay, Ross 1973-1994 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Rappeport, Joseph H. Dr. 1998-2007 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Reeves, Gerald A. Dr. 1969-2001 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Robinson, Charles 1975-2001 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Rodriguez, H. Mrs. undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Roe, Charles 1975-1988 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Rone, Ronald 1976-2007 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Roux, Pete, Mr. Mrs. 1968-1999 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Royall, Tucker 1976-1986 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Rubio, Pedro A., MD, PhD 1996-1999 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Salado Galleries, INC. 1973-1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Samuels, Harry 1972-1980 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Schmidt, J.L. 1976-1996, undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Schroeder, Mr. Mrs. C.L. 1979-2005 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Scott, Morin Jr. (Monty) 1975-1996 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Selden, Jack 1972-2008 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Selden, L.A. 1974-2005, undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Shtofman, Norman 1973-1992 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Smith, B.M.E. 1972-1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Smith, Denman 1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Smith, Robert K. Dr. and Mrs. 1989-1999 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Smithey, Tillman A. 1983, undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Smithart, Claude 1975-1996 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Sowell, Jim 1979-2005 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Spikes, George undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Stallings, Rex 1972-1998 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Stark, Roy L. Mr. Mrs. undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Strasburger, Price, Kelton, Martin, Unis 1973-1991 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Stockley, Mrs. Barbara 1976-1983 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Strong, Jack B. 2008 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Straube, Bessie, Mrs. 1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Summers, Alfred 1973-1992 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Symonds, J. Taft 1975-1976 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Tandy, Dr. Charles 1976-1991 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Tatom, Alan 1975-2000 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Terefenko, C.V. 1981-1985 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Thannish, George 1972-1982 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Thornhill, Felder III 1976-1995 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Tidwell, Roy E. Dr. 1980-1987 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Tiller, David 1972-2007 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Toland, Murray 1975-1979 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Totah, Robert 1972-1987 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Turner, Betty 1972-2001 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Turner, Jack Rice 1970-1991 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Untersee, Walter Mr. Mrs. undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Vageli, Ali, Dr. Mrs. undated (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Vick, Ross and Frances B. 2000-2006 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Vogelson, Jay 1975-2005 (Box 2008-252/11)
      - Vogt, John Mr. Mrs. (Lynn) 1981-1994 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wahlberg, Wesley 1968-1994 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Walton, Ray 1976, undated (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Ward, Charles 1969-2007 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Watson, Russell 1981-1999 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wayland, James E. 1984-1985 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Weeth, Chuck 1970-2006 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Weil, Charles B. 1976, undated (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wells, John 1978-1984 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - White, Christopher Fred 1972-1987 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Whitehead, E.H. 1972-2003 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wiederholdt, J. Lee, Dr. Ed. D. 1990-1991 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wideman, T.E., Jr. 1977-1981 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wilkinson, Tom 1992-2004 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Willeford, Dr. George 1972-1976 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Williams, Charles 1991-2007 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Williams, Hugh 1972-1983 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Williamson, Billy undated (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Wilson, Lee (“Vanguard”) publisher 1979-1982 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Winslow, Dr. Grover 1976-2001 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Yale, A.B. Mr. and Mrs., Hedge, Raymond Jr. 1973-1976 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Zidell, Billy 1972-1995 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Zidell, Rozan 1977-2005 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - Assorted 1976, undated (Box 2008-252/12)
    - Correspondence 1957-2008 (Box 2008-252/12)
      - General 1967-2008 (Box 2008-252/12)
        - 1967-1978 1967-1978 (Box 2008-252/12)
        - 1978-1994 1978-1994 (Box 2008-252/13)
        - 1995-2008 1995-2008 (Box 2008-252/14)
      - Selected 1957, 1972-2008 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Gordon Baxter 1982-1983 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Phil Berquist 1996-2008 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Elton Bomer 1991 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Bob Bowman 1982-1991 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Liz Carpenter 1987-1991 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Dr. Isabella Cunningham 1991-1998, undated (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Simon Dinnerstein 1992-2005 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Embassy of the United States of America, Quito, Ecuador 1977-1987 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Dr. Manfred P. Emmes 1988-2003 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Alma Gunter 1980-1983 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Alexandre Hogue 1993-1994 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Ada Morehead Holland 1988-1998 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Mrs. Jens Jacobsen 1991-1993 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Lady Bird Johnson 1972-2006 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Jim Lehrer 1996-1999 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Jack Lewis 1993 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Al Lowman 1978-2002 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Merrit Mauzey 1957, 1972 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Midwestern State University 1996 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Concerning nomination for State Artist 1973 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - William Owens 1983 (Box 2008-252/14)
        - Rev. Tom Potts 1988-1993 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Charles Robb 1976-2000 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Buck Schiwetz 1982, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
        - John Ben Shepperd 1973 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Smithsonian Institution, Archives of American Art, Texas Project 1983-1984 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Southern Methodist University, Jerry Bywaters Collection 1985-2006 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Leonard Tavernetti 1976-2005 (Box 2008-252/15)
          - Leonard Tavernetti 1976-2005 (Box 2008-252/15)
          - “How I’m Doing?”: My Life With Hildegard undated (Box 2008-252/15)
          - Genealogy undated (Box 2008-252/15)
          - Sagebrush Shangri-La 1998 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - John Tower 1973 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Donald Weismann 1981-2003 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Whitehead Whitehead 1990-1994 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Charles Wilson 1984-1986 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Bryan Woolley 1985-1992, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Valerija and Jennifer Woolvin 1984-2007 (Box 2008-252/15)
    - Selected work files 1968-2008 (Box 2008-252/15)
      - Leann Alspaugh 1992-2007 (Box 2008-252/15)
      - Aaron Bohrod 1975-1997 (Box 2008-252/15)
      - Jerry Brown undated (Box 2008-252/15)
      - Barry Green 1993-2003 (Box 2008-252/15)
      - A.C. Greene 1968-2006, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Personal correspondence 1968-2006 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - Correspondence with Geoffrey Greene 1991-2000, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
        - A Christmas Tree 1973 (Box 2008-252/15)
        - A Personal Country 1968-1969, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
          - A Personal Country 1969, undated (Box 2008-252/15)
          - Correspondence 1968-1969 (Box 2008-252/15)
          - Ink drawings undated (Box 2008-252/16)
          - Sketches undated (Box 2008-252/16)
          - Sketchbook undated (Box 2008-252/16)
        - A Timeless World 1972, undated (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Leon Hale 1983-1998 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Charles Jones 1975-1999 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Rose Marie Sharp Mercado 1974-2008 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - ANCEL NUNN – Paintings and Drawings 1996-1997 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Erma Perry 1977-1991 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Billy Porterfield 1977-2007 (Box 2008-252/16)
        - Billy Porterfield 1977-2007 (Box 2008-252/16)
        - Diddy Waw Diddy 1993-1994 (Box 2008-252/16)
        - Remnants of Change 1990 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Shearer Publishing 1981-1996 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - Texas AM University Press 1977-1992 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - “The Texas Observer”; Joe Holley, William Goyen 1982-1983 (Box 2008-252/16)
      - University of Texas at Tyler 1979-2007 (Box 2008-252/17)
      - James Lewis Wilkins 1972-1997 (Box 2008-252/17)
      - Hiram Williams 1980-2003 (Box 2008-252/17)
      - William D. Wittliff 1965-1995, undated (Box 2008-252/17)
      - Samuel Woolvin 1969-2008 (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Correspondence 1969-2008 (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Photograph undated (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Assorted poetry 1987-1994, undated (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Dreamscapes 1988 (Box 2008-252/17)
        - The Elysian Fields 1987 (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Possessions series 1990 (Box 2008-252/17)
        - Remnants of Change 1989-2002 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Remnants of Change 1990-1995 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Poetic essay drafts 1989 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Poetic essay manuscript undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Manuscript undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Galley proof 1991 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Proof 1991 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Unbound copy undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Dummy book undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Press package 1992 (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Morningtown Press logo undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Brochure layout undated (Box 2008-252/18)
          - Bookkeeping 1990-2002 (Box 2008-252/18)
            - Bookkeeping 1990-1992 (Box 2008-252/18)
            - Accounts receivable 1991-1994 (Box 2008-252/18)
            - Bills paid 1990-2002 (Box 2008-252/18)
            - Remnants of Change, A Sketchbook of Texas, boxed set #38/110 [1988] (Box TBD)
      - Gerhard Wurzer / Gerhard Wurzer Gallery 1981-2001 (Box 2008-252/18)
      - Yevgeny Yevtushenko 1988-2007 (Box 2008-252/18)
        - Yevgeny Yevtushenko 1 1993-2007 (Box 2008-252/18)
        - Yevgeny Yevtushenko 2 1993-2003 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - Introduction to Paintings and Drawings 1996 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - Almost At The End 1988 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - William E. Young 1977-2007 (Box 2008-252/19)
    - Exhibition files 1971-2008 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - The Gaines Farm series 1971-2007 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - Ecuador 1977, undated (Box 2008-252/19)
      - Lufkin Historical and Creative Arts Center / Museum of East Texas 1977-2005 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - The Institute of Texan Cultures 1978-1984 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - “FIRE” exhibition, Contemporary Art Museum, Houston, TX 1978-1979 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - Texas AM University 1986-1989 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - “Carousel Fantasia” Michigan State University Museum 1985-1986 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - Palestine Public Library 1992 (Box 2008-252/19)
      - Tyler Museum of Art 1972-2007 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - Exhibits 1972-1985 1972-1985 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - A Timeless World 1972 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - Exhibits 1996-1999 1996-2007 (Box 2008-252/19)
        - Feb. – Mar. retrospective exhibit 1997-1999 (Box 2008-252/19)
          - Feb. – Mar. retrospective exhibit 1 1997-1999 (Box 2008-252/19)
          - Feb. – Mar. retrospective exhibit 2 1997-1999 (Box 2008-252/19)
          - Feb. – Mar. retrospective exhibit 3 1997-1999 (Box 2008-252/20)
        - “Father and Son” exhibit 2005 2001-2006 (Box 2008-252/20)
        - Tyler Museum of Art 2000-2007 2000-2007 (Box 2008-252/20)
      - Southwest Art Magazine 1973, 1993-1997 (Box 2008-252/20)
      - Longview Museum of Fine Arts 2007-2008 (Box 2008-252/20)
    - Log books 1975-2000 (Box 2008-252/20)
      - Log books 1975-1982 (Box 2008-252/20)
      - Log books 1983-2000 (Box 2008-252/21)
    - Art [circa 1945], 1981-1998, undated (Box 2008-252/22)
      - Ancel Nunn [circa 1945], 1981-1998, undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Assorted undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Catalogues 1986-1993 (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Charcoal drawing undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Greeting cards 1981-1998 (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Morningtown Press logo undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Sketchbooks undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Sketches undated (Box 2008-252/22)
        - Studies for Tyler Museum of Art catalogue 1974 (Box 2008-252/22)
      - William Stephens undated (Box 2008-252/22)
    - Awards 1971-1978 (Box 2008-252/22)
      - Texas Arts Alliance 1977-1978 (Box 2008-252/22)
      - Texas Historical Survey Committe 1971 (Box 2008-252/22)
    - Finance 1968-2002 (Box 2008-252/22)
    - Guest books 1971-2001 (Box 2008-252/22)
    - Newspaper clippings 1943-2007 (Box 2008-252/23)
    - Magazines 1971-1995 (Box 2008-252/23)
    - Miscellaneous 1995-2000, undated (Box 2008-252/23)
  - Reneta Nunn papers 1974-2001
    - Reneta E. Nunn file 1974-2001 (Box 2008-252/23)
    - Writings 1989-2001 (Box 2008-252/23)
    - Prospect clients folder 1983-1989, undated (Box 2008-252/23)
- Stored at Sid Richardson Hall (SRH)
  - Oversized materials 1943, 1967-1987, undated (Box o1)
    - Selected work files 1974, undated
      - Samuel Woolvin undated
        - Remnants of Change undated
          - Layout undated
      - Billy Porterfield 1974, undated
        - Tyler Museum of Art 1974 catalogue “Ancel Nunn” 1974, undated
          - Linen-covered limited edition hardback 1974
          - Sketch undated
      - A.C. Greene undated (Box o2)
        - A Personal Country undated
          - Sketchbook – Early ideas undated
          - Sketches undated
      - “The Texas Observer”; Joe Holley, William Goyen undated
        - Illustration etchings undated
    - Executed artworks undated
      - 7503 The Golden Spike undated
    - Exhibition files 1974
      - Tyler Museum of Art 1974
        - “Ancel E. Nunn” 1974 catalogue 1974
          - Linen-covered limited edition hardback 1974
          - Studio copy 1974
    - Art 1967-1975, undated (Box o3)
      - Ancel Nunn 1972-1974, undated
        - Catalogues 1974
          - Tyler Museum of Art (paperback) 1974
        - Lithograph plates undated
          - 9602 “Compromise Compromised” undated
        - Pencil drawings undated
        - Tethered Nomad undated
        - The Texas Star newspaper feature 1972
      - William Young undated
        - “Great Divide” etching undated
      - Charles Jones 1967-1975
    - Photographs undated
      - Book Jacket, Texas Women undated
    - Personal undated (Box o4)
      - Philosophy / thoughts undated
    - Patron files 1987
      - Weeth, Chuck 1987
    - Selected work files 1982-1983, undated
      - Billy Porterfield 1982-1983
        - Dreamscapes 1982-1983
      - Samuel Woolvin undated
        - Remnants of Change undated
          - Sketches undated
    - Art undated
      - Ancel Nunn undated
        - Reproductions undated
        - Paintings and Drawings undated
        - Sketches undated
        - In Search of Reality undated
      - JoAnn Tunnell undated
    - Art 1943, undated (Drawer 2.116/OD1448)
      - Ancel Nunn 1943, undated
        - Reproductions undated
        - Pencil drawings undated
        - Watercolor 1943
        - Lithographs – “Object Found”, “The Fallen Vision of Isa-Tai”, “The Elysian Fields”, unknown undated
        - Lithograph plate undated
      - Hiram Williams undated
        - Lithographs – “Man with small sad eye”, “Stretched Man”, “Man with Nose askew” undated
    - Awards 1978
      - Texas Arts Alliance 1978
  - Framed artwork 1957-1965, 1977, undated (Drawer 2.116/OD1446)
    - Aaron Bohrod undated
    - Geoffrey Greene undated
    - Charles Jones 1977
      - The Essence of Existence 1977
    - W. Slattery undated
    - William Young undated (Drawer 2.116/OD1447)
      - Sancturn undated
    - Ancel Nunn undated
      - [Man in hat] undated
      - [Girl] 1965
      - [Tribal mask] 1957 (Box TBD)
      - [Girl and shell] undated (Box TBD)
  - Photographs 1968-2001, undated (Box 19)
    - Important old photos undated
    - Ancel Nunn 1968-1978, 1998-1999, undated
      - Prints 1998-1999, undated
      - Slides 1968-1978
    - Artworks undated
    - Exhibitions 1977-1986
    - Deframed 1976-1978, 1999, undated
      - Ancel Nunn 1978
      - Photo of bird taking flight by William Wittliff 1976
      - Billy Porterfield undated
      - Yevgeny Yevtuschenko and Reneta Nunn 1999
    - The Foundry 1972-1973, undated
    - Archives 1984, undated
    - Assorted undated
    - Photo albums 1993-2001, undated
      - Ancel, studio, and Badenthal Ranch in Sisterdale, Texas 1994, undated
      - House and studio 1993-2001, undated
      - Public relations photos undated
      - Tyler Museum of Art retrospective exhibit 1999
  - Scrapbooks 1971-1983 (Box TBD)
    - Scrapbook 1971-1980 1971-1980
    - Scrapbook 1978-1983 1978-1983
  - Cassette tapes 1983, 1996, undated (Box 2X70a)
    - Donald Weismann tapes 1996, undated
    - University of Texas at Tyler lecture tapes 1983
  - Video tapes 1974, 1983, 1996, undated (Box 3W199)
    - The University of Texas Institute of Texan Cultures at San Antonio, All Things Considered: Artist Ancel Nunn undated
    - Yevgeny Yevtushenko / Poet-Russian undated
    - Houston Youth Orchestra 6HYO – Yevtushenko – May 1996 1996
    - Ancel E. Nunn, Lecture Paris, TX Junior College 1983
    - Sony L-500 video cassette undated
    - Ancel Nunn – Palestine, KERA-TV (PBS Channel 13) undated
    - Ancel Nunn, Bill Porterfield, Bill Commedore, Rudy Pharis undated
    - Ancel Nunn / 74 Channel 13 PBS All Things Considered undated
    - Ancel NUNN – Palestine / All Things Considered / Lecture and Proud of East Texas undated
  - Restricted: Computer Disks undated (Box 3H13)
    - 3.5” floppy disks, Ancel Nunn book undated